Correspondence of American Federation of Labor President William Green on Microfilm 5402 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Correspondence of American Federation of Labor President William Green on Microfilm
1926-1951
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Federation of Labor
Green, William
5402 mf
5.89 cubic feet
53 microfilm reels
Correspondence, photographs, microfilm.
The collection consists of 43 rolls of microfilm of all letters sent out over William Green's signature during his term as President of the A.F.L. from 1926 to 1952. The first roll is number 2.
5651130
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 07, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 02, 2015
Biographical / Historical
William Green (1873-1952) was an American trade union leader. He is remembered for serving as the President of the American Federation of Labor from 1924 to 1952. Green became president of the AFL following the death of Samuel Gompers. In 1933, he persuaded President Franklin D. Roosevelt to appoint him to the Labor Advisory Council of the National Recovery Administration. He is also remembered for presiding over the split in the AFL which led to the founding of the congress of Industrial Organizations.
Under Green the AFL moved to a more cooperative style when politicking for labor. He promoted for a cutback in the hours of labor, believing that it would increase worker's living standards.
As a result of his support the Norris-La Guardia Act of 1932 was passed, directed at reducing the practice o f labor restrictions and elimination of "yellow dog contracts". Green was also succesful in gaining federation support for a national unemployment insurance system sponsored mostly by employer donations. In 1935 he helped with the passage of the National Labor Relations Act, aimed at empoering workers' rights to organize and take part in collective bargaining. And in 1938 Green helped to pass the Fair Labor Standards Act, becoming the first federal law in instituting minimum wages and the 40-hour work week.
Scope and Contents
Letters sent out with William Green's signature during his term as president of the A.F. of L.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5431 mf: Letterpress Copybooks of Samuel Gompers and William Green, Presidents on Microfilm 5760 mf: American Federation of Labor Records, Part 2 on Microfilm 5761 mf: William Green Papers on Microfilm
Labor unions -- United States -- History -- Sources.; Green, William, 1872-1952; American Federation of Labor
5651130
- President Green's & Sec. Morrison's Misc., 1 (Reel 1a)
- President Green's Misc., 1 (Reel 2a)
- President Green's Misc., 1 (Reel 3a)
- President Green's Misc., 1 (Reel 4a)
- President Green's Misc., 1 (Reel 5a)
- President Green's Misc., 1 (Reel 6a)
- President Green's Misc. File -- Feb. thru Sept. 1949-1952, 1 (Reel 7a)
- President Green's Misc., 1 (Reel 8a)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: April 1926, 1 (Reel 121)
  Scope and Contents
  positive
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: November 1926, 1 (Reel 122)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: August 1927, 1 (Reel 123)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: June 1928, 1 (Reel 124)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: April 1929, 1 (Reel 125)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: January 1930, 1 (Reel 126)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: September 1930, 1 (Reel 127)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: April 1931, 1 (Reel 128)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: January 1932, 1 (Reel 129)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: October 1932, 1 (Reel 130)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: June 1933, 1 (Reel 131)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: September 1933, 1 (Reel 132)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: December 1933, 2 (Reel 132)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: March 1934, 1 (Reel 134)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: June 1934, 1 (Reel 135)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: October 1934, 1 (Reel 136)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: January 1935, 1 (Reel 137)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: May 1935, 1 (Reel 138)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: September 1935, 1 (Reel 139)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: March 1936, 1 (Reel 140)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: August 1936, 1 (Reel 141)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: February 1937, 1 (Reel 142)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: June 1937, 1 (Reel 143)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: December 1937, 1 (Reel 144)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: May 1938, 1 (Reel 145)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: November 1938, 1 (Reel 146)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: April 1939, 1 (Reel 147)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: October 1939, 1 (Reel 148)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: April 1940, 1 (Reel 149)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: October 1940, 1 (Reel 150)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: March 1941, 1 (Reel 151)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: September 1941, 1 (Reel 152)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: April 1942, 1 (Reel 153)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: November 1942, 1 (Reel 154)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: August 1943, 1 (Reel 155)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: June 1944, 1 (Reel 156)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: May 1945, 1 (Reel 157)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: May 1946, 1 (Reel 158)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: April 1947, 1 (Reel 159)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: May 1948, 1 (Reel 160)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: July 1949, 1 (Reel 161)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: July 1950, 1 (Reel 162)
- Record Group C-2 -- William Green Letter Books -- Begins: October 1951, 1 (Reel 163)
- Wm Green, Pres. AFL - Correspondence -- 1942, 1 (Reel 166)